HR GENERALIST

Summary

Energetic, Bilingual Human Resources Professional offering $\hat{A} \sim 11$ years of extensive and successful experience administering various HR plans and procedures. Emphasis on recruitment/retention, management and HR principles & practices. Expertise in employee relations and organization development through education, and experience, seeks a similar role to produce immediate growth contribution to a rewarding company. Highlights

- Hiring and retention
- Training and development
- Compensation and benefits
- New hire orientation
- Compensation administration/payroll
- Mediation expertise
- Employee relations
- Labor agreements
- Regulatory compliance
- Knowledgeable in all HR Systems

Experience

Quantitech Wallops Island, VA HR Generalist 12/2014 to Current

- Develops Human Resources policies, procedures, plans and budgets.
- The safety of the workforce for recruitment, development and compensation of a superior workforce.
- Develops an employee-oriented culture that emphasizes quality, continuous improvement and high performance.
- Conduct new employee orientation to foster positive attitude toward organizational objectives.
- Serve as a link between management and employees by handling questions, interpreting and administering contracts and helping resolve work-related problems.
- Serve on the executive management team and assists and advises company managers about Human Resources issues with regards to compensation, benefits, compliance, organizational development, HRIS, training & development and employee relations.
- Review and provide comments on the adequacy of documents and took necessary steps to cure any deficiencies.
- Create and implement the exit and interview program process.
- Run the bi-weekly payroll process.
- Increase the employee base by 15 % to meet changing staffing needs.

Quantitech Washington Navy Yard, DC HR Generalist 02/2013 to 12/2014

- Administered various HR plans and procedures for all company personnel; assist in development and implementation of personnel policies and procedures; Ensure employee compliance.
- Conducted recruitment efforts for all exempt and non-exempt personnel for shop and office which including temporary employees for each.
- Assisted in evaluation of reports, decisions, and results of department in relation to established goals.
- Recommend new approaches, policies, and procedures to effect continual improvements in efficiency of department and services performed.
- Conducted employment verifications and investigations.
- Developed company personnel policies, standard operating procedures and employee handbooks.
- Educateed and advised employees on group health plans, voluntary benefits and 401(k) retirement plans.
- Developed and facilitated all new-hire orientations.
- Developed and enforced company policy and procedures relating to all phases of human resources activity.
- Facilitated the criminal background check process for new hires.
- Managed the employee offer process with 100% at the exempt level.
- Processed unemployment claims and acted as the company representative at unemployment hearings.

First Transit West Hartford , CT Human Resource Manager 10/2008 to 01/2013

- Developed, implemented and coordinated policies and procedures for all Human Resources functions such as recruiting, wage/salary administration and health programs.
- Directed employee performance management program.
- Promoted the opportunity for a formal discussion by employees and their supervisors to review overall work performance, objectives, and career development.
- Partnered with management team members on issues involving employee relations such as terminations, suspensions, EEOC claims and rule interpretations.
- Educated and advised employees on group health plans, voluntary benefits and 401(k) retirement plans.
- Developed company personnel policies, standard operating procedures and employee handbooks.
- Developed and facilitated all new-hire orientations.
- Conducted employment verifications and investigations.
- Developed and enforced company policy and procedures relating to all phases of human resources activity.
- Facilitated the criminal background check process for new hires.
- Managed all aspects of leave administration, including employee notifications and vendor management, disability programs and health benefits.
- Acted as liaison between employees and insurance carriers to resolve problems and clarify benefits.
- Processed unemployment claims and acted as the companyrepresentative at unemployment hearings.

Elior Sarasota, FL Staffing Manager 10/2004 to 09/2008

- Conducted background checks on candidates by obtaining information from law enforcement officials, previous employers and references.
- Explained employee compensation, benefits, schedules, working conditions and promotion opportunities.
- Coordinated employment offers with management and extended offers to selected candidates.
- Reviewed and confirmed that all final paid hours corresponded with timesheets and state laws.
- Evaluated timecards for accuracy on the regular and overtime hours.
- Reviewed human resource paperwork for accuracy and completeness by verifying, collecting and correcting additional data.
- Completed employee employment verifications and unemployment paperwork in a timely manner.

Education

 $BBA: Human \ Resource \ Management \ 2004 \ Sam \ Houston \ State \ University \ , \ City \ , \ State \ , \ USA \ Minor \ in \^A \ International \ Business \ Coursework \ in \ Human \ Resource \ Management \ Coursework \ in \ Business \ Administration$

Associate of Science : Liberal Arts 2000 North Harris Community College , City , State , USA 3.8 Â GPA Liberal Arts Skills

ADA, ADP, benefits, clarify, employee relations, human resource, Human Resources, HR, insurance, law enforcement, mediation, MS Office, office, SharePoint, Organizational, performance management, personnel, policies, promotion, recruiting, recruitment, employee handbooks, vendor management